ancient Chinese paintings are both
Witnesses of Chinese history and
inheritance of Chinese culture however
most of them have suffered from varying
degrees of cultivating problems
to extend the life of this color faded
paintings restorers must first infer
their original colors with faithful
references and then perform Trio and
error colorization to achieve
satisfactory results
this process is challenging and time
consuming and usually takes months to
years for one painting
to improve the efficiency of color
restoration we follow the congruence
principle of ancient Chinese paintings
and poems which hosts that paintings and
poems are two congruent artistic forms
to borrow scenery to express emotions
a specific manifestation of those
principle is that paintings and poems
often utilize the same objects to depict
the scenery and convey congruent
conceptual feelings
in Chinese culture this objects and
conceptual feelings are respectively
referred to you as imagery and ideorum
however two challenges still exist when
applying this principle
first ancient Chinese poems are high
level abstract words that are difficult
for cross model alignment second it is
also not easy to find correct color
schemes in large scale reference
paintings
to overcome these two challenges we
collaborated with two restorers with
more than years of experience restoring
ancient Chinese paintings
based on their interviews we summarize
the list of user requirements and
proposed a novel interactive system
called p colorizer for color faded
painting p-colorizer uses a poem
painting kangaroons module to search for
Relevant reference paintings based on
its idea Rim congruent poem designs
visualizations to help color scheme
analysis and employs a user-guided
colorization module to support fast
colorization
to prove the effectiveness of the
congruence principle of paintings and
poems we explored how the poem painting
conference module understands the idea
Ram expressed by a specific method
called borrowing beautiful scenery to
express negative emotion in this method
often utilizes bright colors to conceal
negative emotions which cannot be
directly expressed
concretely We compare the color
histograms of reference paintings
searched based on the color faded
painting and its saudium congruent poems
separately
found that the reference painting
searched based on the idrum congruent
poem involved more bright colors which
means that the poem painting Congress
module appears to understand did ROM
however we also explored how the poem
painting congruence module understands
two other ID ramps expressed by Boring
beautiful scenery to express positive
emotions and borrowing chaos scenery to
express negative emotions respectively
we also presented a real case to show
how the restorer utilizes P colorizer to
conduct color restoration
after uploading the painting to be
restored with this idea Ram congruent
poem The ReStore first browsed the
entire painting to understand the fading
of different imagery then he used the
lasso tool and the grid-based tax
component to construct the query of
reference painting such
after clicking on the search button he
noticed the main Dynasty had largest
number of reference paintings which also
showed High congruence schools hence had
decided to view the paintings of this
dynasty first and clicked on the
corresponding button
in the glyph bass scatter plot he found
two painting clusters had different
color schemes he clicked on the glyph of
painting a and then viewed his color
scheme in the hierarchical bar chart
for the color scheme he used a selection
function of the hierarchical bar chart
to control which colors will be
displayed in the mountain matte first
a period of exploration he found that
only one blue color has not appeared in
the dynasty where the color faded
painting was created therefore he added
painting a to the reference list
after confirming the correctness of the
idea Ram understood by the poem painting
congruence module he utilized the fast
colorization tools to colorize The Faded
imagery
following several rounds of iteration he
chose to export the current restoration
version for subsequent restoration work
thank you for watching